Guide to the Cornell University School for Missionaries Records,1933-1964.
Cornell University School for Missionaries Records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cornell University School for Missionaries records, 1933-1964.
21-34-1476
Cornell University. School for Missionaries.
1.5 cubic ft.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes correspondence and memoranda; letters of inquiry about the school; registration lists; completed student registration and information blanks; pamphlets; letters from past students; information about the Iowa School for Missionaries; newsletters, GREEN PASTURES DAILY; student directories; "Thumb-Nail Sketch Books" of student biographies; class schedules; and issues of AGRICULTURAL MISSION NOTES, a quarterly.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
The Cornell School for Missionaries annually offered four weeks of courses to missionaries on furlough who wished a better understanding of the principles of agriculture, nutrition and health, rural education, and sociology.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes correspondence and memoranda; letters of inquiry about the school; registration lists; completed student registration and information blanks; pamphlets; letters from past students; information about the Iowa School for Missionaries; newsletters, GREEN PASTURES DAILY; student directories; "Thumb-Nail Sketch Books" of student biographies; class schedules; and issues of AGRICULTURAL MISSION NOTES, a quarterly.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University. School for Missionaries.; Cornell University.
Titles:
Green pastures daily.; Agricultural mission notes.
Subjects:
Missionaries--Leaves and furloughs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
  - Missionary School Policy, 1933-1942 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Missionary School, Progress and Enrollment, 1933-1942 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Letters of Past Students, 1933-1943 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - S.H. Leger, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - The Iowa School for Missionaries (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - The 1936 School, The 1937 School, The 1938 School, 1936-1938 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - The 1939 School (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - The 1940 School (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - The 1941 School (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Missionary School announcement, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - The 1942 School (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Suggestions of 1942 School (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Missionary School (cancelled) suggestions, letters, etc., 1943 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Missionary School, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Missionary School, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Missionary Short Course in Relief and Rehabilition, September 17-October 26, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - 16th Annual Cornell School for Missionaries, January 7-February 1, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - 17th Annual Cornell School for Missionaries, January 6-31, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - 18th Annual one-month short course for Missionaries, January 5-30, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - 19th Annual one-month course for Missionaries, January 4-28, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - 20th Annual one-month course for Missionaries, January 3-27, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - 21st Annual short course for Missionaries, January 2-26, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - 22nd Annual School for Missionaries, January 7-February 1, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - 23rd Annual Cornell School for Missionaries, January 6-30, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - 24th Annual Cornell School for Missionaries, January 5-29, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - 25th Annual Short Course for Missionaries, January 4-28, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 26th Annual One-Month course for Missionaries, January 3-27, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 27th Annual short course for Missionaries, January 8-February 1, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 28th Annual Cornell School for Missionaries, January 14-31, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 29th Annual Cornell School for Missionaries, February 10-27, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - 30th Annual Cornell School for Missionaries, February 9-26, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Survey, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Letters Re: address (Box 5, Folder 8)